周六\N晚上8点\N　\N
婚礼前22小时
"接下来就是见证奇迹的时刻"
"Let's get this party started."
嘿 麻烦按一下那个按钮好吗
Hey, can you push the button?
不要动那个按钮
Do not touch that button.
-就小小的按一下下  -不要按
-Just give it a little push. -Don't push it.
-就轻轻的按一下  -别听他的
-Just push it a little. -Don't listen to him.
-就按下去一丢丢 按一半 一半  -碰都不要碰那个按钮
-Half of it, halfway, halfway... -Don't even touch it.
为什么不让我碰这按钮
Why can't I push the button?
因为无论什么时候 只要巴尼看到一个按钮 只要是个按钮
Because whenever Barney sees a button-- any button--
他都要去按
He has to push it.
抱歉啊
Sorry.
你怎么这么火大
Why are you so mad?
因为我婚礼的预演晚宴呢
Because my rehearsal dinner
十分钟之前就该开始了
was supposed to start ten minutes ago.
这会儿我本来应该头也不抬的啃着
But instead of stuffing my face
餐前的法式小点心
with hors d'oeuvres
我已经期待了好几个月的小点心啊
that I have been dreaming about for months,
而现在怎么样 我在真人激光枪的
I am in a laser tag
保安办公室里面
security office,
等着警察来逮捕我的未婚夫
waiting for the police to arrest my fiance
因为他引起了一场骚乱
for causing a disturbance.
嘿 你叫我"未婚夫"了耶
Hey, you said "Fiance"
真好
That's a good sign.
现在我们按按那按钮 你说怎么样啊
Now what do you say we give that old button a push?
仔细看看这张脸 巴尼 好吗
Take a good look at this face, Barney, okay?
好好记住 警钟长鸣
'Cause it'll be useful for the future.
这就是我"火冒三丈"的表情
This is my "Pretty mad" Face.
呃 那好吧 这下我们有麻烦了
Well, then, we've got a problem.
因为它看上去和"好饿哦"表情惊人的相似啊
'Cause it looks a lot like your "Pretty hungry" Face.
我的无花果培根卷吃不上了啊
I'm missing the bacon-wrapped figs!
按一下那个按钮求你啦
Please push the button!
老爸\N　　　  　　 老妈\N　　 　　 浪漫史\N　　  　　　　第九季  第十二集\N
S09E12 Rehearsal Dinner
翻译: @小白是憎恶 @阿狸小H @卟哒哒伽玛\N@云湾森川如风 @肉鸭大魔王\N时间轴+压制: @晒小花 @阿狸小H
统筹+校对+后期\N盼团聚等归期肉鸭鸭 行千里待梦圆小花花
HIMYM字幕组 倾情奉献
这里怎么这么冷啊
Why is it so cold in here?
你们是想冻得我逼供还是怎样
You trying to get me to talk or something?
没这个意思
Not really.
实际上 如果你能好好坐在那里保持安静...
In fact, if you could just sit there quietly...
好吧 我全招了
Fine, I'll talk.
一切都要追溯到几个月前
It all started a few months ago,
我想出了史上最棒的主意 没有之一
when I had the most awesome idea ever.
真人激光枪预演晚宴
Laser tag rehearsal dinner!
几个月之前
这简直是你史上最烂的主意了 没有之一
That might be the worst idea you've ever had,
而且你的馊主意可不少
which is saying a lot.
你们倒是说出一个我出过的馊主意
Name one bad idea I've ever had.
不含谷蛋白的可食用内裤
Gluten-free edible panties.
面包夹着热狗插根棍
Hot dog on a stick on a bun.
可充气性爱玩具救生艇
Inflatable sex toy life raft.
隆胸手术频道
The breast augmentation channel.
纯麦芽威士忌卷
Single malt Scotch tape.
还有你去竞选市长那次
The time you ran for mayor.
还有12000个纽扣上面写着
I still have 12,000 buttons that say,
"我只在乎我裤子里的那一票"
"The only poll I care about is in my pants."
巴尼 策划婚礼
Barney, planning a wedding
需要两个人不停地妥协
is all about compromise.
你还记不记得那天晚上
Do you remember that one night,
就在我们订婚不久之后
right after we got engaged?
到底要在哪里举行婚礼呢
Where is this wedding gonna be, anyway?
四个月前
要我说啊 在加拿大举行婚礼倒是挺不错的
You know, I thought it might be nice to get married in Canada
我是说 毕竟我是在那长大的 而且...
I mean, it's where I'm from, and...
好吧
Okay.
有什么就说吧
Let's have it. Get it over with,
尽情吐槽吧 别把你们憋坏了
get it all out of your system.
我是新郎
I'm the groom,
我是新郎 让我先来
I'm the groom, I might as well start.
去加拿大 怎么
Canada? What, are we gonna
我们是要伴着实验碰撞假人的歌走上红毯吗
walk down the aisle to Crash Test Dummies?
实验碰撞假人 加拿大摇滚乐队
下一棒 马修
Play's to Marshall.
加拿大 我们要去干什么
Canada? What are you gonna do,
是租一架普通的狗拉雪橇呢 还是要可伸缩雪橇呢
hire a regular dog sled or a stretch?
加拿大
Canada?
你们是在提姆•霍顿登记结婚的吗
Are you registered at Tim Hortons?
提姆•霍顿 加拿大最大的咖啡连锁店
加拿大
Canada.
是不是风琴手要戴着
Oh, does the organist play
连指手套弹风琴啊
wearing mittens?
加拿大 新娘子带着连指手套
Canada? How are you gonna
要怎么要才能把戒指戴在指头上啊
slip the ring on the bride's finger if she's wearing mittens?
连续吐槽连指手套两次
Two mitten jokes in a row?
看来 你们的梗快要用完了吗
So... you're pretty much done, then?
孩子们 疯狂大吐槽才刚刚开始
Kids, we weren't even close.
加拿大
Canada.
婚礼请柬上要怎么写呢
What do we ask on the wedding invitation?
"请问想吃麋鹿还是驼鹿"
"Will you be having the elk or the moose?"
加拿大
Canada.
怎么 你们要穿什么走红毯
What, are you gonna walk down the aisle
雪鞋吗
wearing snowshoes?!
加拿大
Canada.
怎么 是不是宾客们过去都要买个临时医疗保险
What, is everyone gonna have access to universal healthcare
省的万一有人还要担心万一得了什么重病
so no one has to choose between going bankrupt
就得倾家荡产了吗
and treating a life-threatening illness?
吐槽游客去加拿大要买临时医疗保险获得医保
加拿大
Canada?
你们跳第一支舞的时候 乐队要奏什么呢
W-What's the band gonna play for your first dance?
实验碰撞假人吗
Crash Test Dummies?
知道吗 笑点在于
See, it's funny
哪有人会在婚礼上请乐队啊
'cause who gets a band?
OMG 这应该是泰德一直反对罗宾婚礼请乐队的梗又重现了吧
够了 这只是灵光一闪而已
Enough. It was just an idea.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
认真的说 罗宾 在纽约办婚礼更简单可行一些
Seriously, Robin, doing it here in New York
因为我们所有的朋友
would be easier, since all of our friends
还有我们好多家人都在这呢
and a lot of our family are here.
但是... 我希望这场婚礼能如你所愿
But... I want you to have the wedding that you want.
所以 如果你真的想去加拿大
So if it's Canada...
那就说出来吧
just say the word.
然后再用法语说一遍
And then say it again in French.
吐槽加拿大的官方语言为英语和法语两种
看 我都做出让步了
See? I compromised.
好吧
Fine.
那我们就办一场高端 上档次的预演晚宴吧
We'll just have a nice, tasteful rehearsal dinner.
不如选个法国餐厅怎么样
Maybe at a French restaurant.
我正好知道个好地方
I know just the place.
你知道的餐厅叫什么名字啊
What's the name of the restaurant?
激 光枪大战
La... ser tag.
我一直在想
You know, I was thinking about
你们结婚的时候 我要送你们什么礼物
what to get you guys for a wedding gift.
你们知道的
As you know,
哥可是传说中的"结婚礼物大师"
I'm kind of the wedding gift master.
而且 现在正一直讨论着的预演晚宴
And, well, all this talk of the rehearsal dinner
给了我一个超赞的点子
gives me a fantastic idea.
我一直都想
I've been meaning
再去上钢琴课来着
to start taking piano lessons again.
不行
No.
-没时间让你弹钢琴  -求你们了
-No piano time. -Guys!
就让我表演点什么吧
Just let me perform something.
我会...我会弹得天花乱坠
I'll-I'll tickle the keys.
效果一定精彩绝伦
It'll be great.
就算你穿成李伯拉斯的样子都不行
Not even if you dressed up as Liberace.
Liberace 美国20世纪五六十年代著名艺人和钢琴家
我要是真穿成李伯拉斯那样儿呢
What if I dressed up as Liberace?
-成交  -成交
-Sold! -Sold.
然后 就没有然后了
And that was the end of it.
直到我的单身派对
Until my bachelor party.
啧啧
Uh-oh.
我猜猜看
Let me guess:
派对上肯定有个脱衣舞娘
there was a stripper.
你玩儿得挺美
You had a little fun.
备不住还禁不住怂恿 拍了几张少儿不宜的照片
Maybe took some ill-advised pictures.
然后紧接着
Next thing you know,
她就开始以此要挟勒索你 直到你几近破产
she's blackmailing you into bankruptcy,
你的医学学位就得挂在
and your medical degree's hanging on the wall
某真人激光枪游戏厅保安部的墙上
of a laser tag security office!
没有啊
No.
我单身派对那晚 我的哥们儿们把我带到了
The night of my bachelor party, my friends took me
一个屎到爆的破旅馆
to a crappy hotel,
把我前未婚妻请来当脱衣舞娘
hired my ex-fiancée to be the stripper,
我输了好几千块钱 而我最好的朋友
I lost thousands of dollars, and my best friend
连手都被人砍了
even had his hand cut off.
这本会是我人生中
It would've been
最糟糕的一个晚上
the worst night of all time
但这一切 都只是我
if the whole thing hadn't been
既有美丽又有魅力的未婚妻
a prank planned by
一手策划的充满惊喜的恶作剧
my beautiful, amazing fiancee.
她让我跌落地狱 就是为了让我
She put me through hell just to give me the best
拥有人生中最棒的惊喜 这里面还包括了
surprise of my life...which, p.S.,included an appearance
我最喜欢的演员的出场
by my favorite actor--
不属于A片范畴的
non-porn category.
哇 听起来挺酷的
Wow, that sounds pretty cool.
可不是嘛 唯一不酷的就是
Yeah. Except pretty not cool,
这个人嘴上一直说什么会再回敬我一个
because he kept talking about how he was gonna get me back,
然后 就在派对几天后 还真就...
and sure enough, a few days later...
罗宾 有些话我真的不知道该怎么跟你说
Robin, there's no good way to say this.
我犯了一个天大的错误
I've made a huge mistake.
这婚我没法结了
I can't go through with the wedding.
你说什么
What?
真的非常对不起
I'm so sorry.
只是 我...我必须在
I-I just... I had to tell you
一切再也无可挽回之前告诉你
before it was too late.
天啊 你是认真的吗
Oh, my God, you're serious.
是
Yeah.
而且这里是我的公寓
And since this is my apartment,
所以 我觉得你应该搬出去了
I think that you should move out.
行啊
Fine.
狗狗
Puppies!
我知道 超棒的恶作剧 是不
I know. Great prank, right?
简直糟糕透顶
That is awful.
你丫绝壁是个怪胎
You're a frickin' weirdo.
妥妥儿的怪胎
Such a weirdo.
小心点 别弄脏了袍子
Careful, watch the robe.
但是吧
Anyway,
因为某些只有你们和罗宾能理解
for reasons only you guys and Robin
而像我这样的正常人所不能理解的原因
but nobody normal like me would understand,
罗宾变得超暴躁
she got cranky.
然后立下规矩
And she laid down the law.
不许再搞惊喜
No more surprises.
但是你明明爱死惊喜了嘛
But you love surprises.
你爱惊喜就跟我爱舔自己一样
Almost as much as I love lickin' myself!
这话是我说的 不是狗狗说的
That was me talking, not the puppy.
巴尼 惊喜这东西很难收场的
Barney, the surprises are out of hand
不能再搞惊喜了
and they have to stop.
-行吗  -但是...
-Deal? -But...
-行吗  -屁屁...
-Deal. -Butt...
巴尼
Barney...
好啦
Fine.
deal还同时有小弟弟的意思
哦了
Deal.
老天
Man.
这个"不许再搞惊喜"的规矩
This whole "No more surprises" thing
太不公平了
is so unfair.
谁会这么干啊
Who does that?
巴尼 "不再有惊喜"
Barney, the "No more surprises" thing
是婚姻中最好的部分
is the best part of being married.
真的 每天早晨我醒来的时候
It's true. When I wake up in the morning,
我连莉莉的呼吸是什么味道的都能一清二楚
I know what Lily's breath is gonna smell like.
她的呼吸 就像玫瑰一样香甜
It's like... roses.
难道你真的希望在你和罗宾婚后的生活里
Do you really want a marriage
你每天都需要琢磨
where you have this paranoia
罗宾有没有偷偷摸摸的
that Robin's hiding around every corner,
搞些什么新恶作剧来回敬你吗
planning to get you back with some crazy new prank?
你说的一点错都没有
You're absolutely right.
谢谢你 莉莉
Thank you, Lily.
不对 那...是我说的 我在这儿呢
No, th... that was me, over here.
他根本没在听
He wasn't listening.
如果你们想告诉我的...
If you guys are saying
就是你们刚才说的
what I think you're saying...
非常有可能不是 你继续说
Probably not. Go on.
...那你们一定就是说...
...then that must mean...
不是 我们没那个意思
No, it doesn't.
...罗宾在为我策划一个
...that Robin is planning a surprise
真人激光枪惊喜预演晚宴
laser tag rehearsal dinner!
伙计 罗宾根本没有在策划
Dude, Robin is not planning
什么真人激光枪惊喜预演晚宴好嘛
a surprise laser tag rehearsal dinner.
不对 她有
Yes, she is.
-不 她没有  -不 她肯定有
-No, she isn't.  -Yes, she is.
不 我才没有
No, I'm not!
不 她有的
Yes, she is.
不 她没有
No, she isn't.
那她又是为什么
Then why did she pretend
装作在嘲笑这主意有多傻呢
to ridicule it as an idiotic idea?
因为这主意本来就傻透了
Because it is an idiotic idea.
如果罗宾真的
If Robin actually was
在策划什么惊喜
planning a surprise,
她至少会告诉她的首席伴娘吧
don't you think she would tell her maid of honor?
她没告诉你你因为你根本守不住秘密
She didn't tell you 'cause you can keep a secret
就像我的牙医总丢车钥匙
the way my dentist keeps his car keys.
你们不认识他啊 不过他确实总弄丢
You don't know him, but he's lost them...
两次呢
like, twice.
其实是 只有一次是丢的
Actually, just once, and...
另一次是放另一个口袋里了
that time they were in his other pocket.
我守不住秘密吗
I can't keep a secret?
他说的有道理 莉莉
He does have a point, Lily.
你在大嘴跑风方面已经非常有名了
You're kind of famous for the old blabbity-blabbity.
嘿
Hey.
和黛比的午餐如何
How was lunch with Debbie?
好极 她怀孕了
Great. She's pregnant!
呜
Oops.
我不该告诉别人的
I'm not supposed to tell anybody. Why not?
因为她正在打离婚
Because she's getting a divorce.
妈蛋
Damn it!
黛比正闹离婚
Debbie's getting a divorce?
嗯 她把她老公捉奸在床了
Yeah, she walked in on her husband having sex.
搞毛啊 莉莉
Oh! Come on, Lily.
呃 也不用什么细节都说出来吧
Well, maybe we don't need to know every gory...
还是和一个男的
With a man.
你就不能闭嘴嘛 艾尔德林女士
Will you get it together, Aldrin?!
你没事吧 莉莉
You okay, Lily?
而那个男人正是搞大黛比肚子的
And that guy's the father of the baby.
贵圈 真乱
我回去躺一会
I gotta go lie down.
于是就到今天早些时候
Which brings us to earlier today,
罗宾在布置假的预演晚宴时
when Robin was setting up the decoy rehearsal dinner,
连酒都是假的
complete with fake booze.
预演晚宴前一小时
把这个当威士忌蒙混过去啊
Trying to pass this off as Scotch,
我们都知道这其实是苹果汁
and we all know it's apple juice.
喝苹果汁呛嗓子了
Typical apple juice burn.
没错 巴尼 这酒是真的
Yes, Barney, the booze is real.
吃的也是真的
The food is real.
哦 说到吃的 无花果培根卷在哪儿呢
Ooh, speaking of which, where are the bacon-wrapped figs?
大概在
Probably at...
真人激光枪游戏厅了吧
...the laser tag place,
那儿不才是真正的预演晚宴举办的地方么
where the real rehearsal dinner's going down.
是不是这样 西奥多
Isn't that right, Theodore?
巴尼 没有什么真人激光枪
Barney, there is no laser tag.
咱们就在这儿好好吃顿饭
We're gonna have a nice dinner,
喝点酒 然后
some drinks, and then,
按照罗宾说的
according to Robin,
如果她的伊迪斯姑妈喝得够醉
if her Aunt Edith gets drunk enough,
她就会把假发摘下来 然后他们就能拿它打冰球了
she'll take off her wig and they'll play hockey with it.
胡说八道
Poppycock!
你知道她会怎么做的
You know how she's gonna do it,
你也会如实告诉我的
and you're gonna tell me!
还是我要把脸凑得更近点
Or do I have to get my face
你才会告诉我
even closer to yours?
嘿
Hey.
你为什么不把脸
How come you're not getting
跟我的脸贴近点呢
uncomfortably close to my face?
我也有可能知道内情啊
I could be in on it, too.
可不嘛 莉莉
'Course you could, Lil.
我能保守秘密的
I can keep a secret.
莉莉哟 快别逗我了
Lily, don't make me laugh.
我要是信你能保守秘密
I'd trust you with a secret
就跟我信马修会抖出秘密一样傻
as much as I'd trust Marshall with Pop Secret.
我能保守秘密的
I can keep a secret!
为了保守秘密我能守口如瓶
I can keep a secret real good.
我保守秘密的时候 就跟这秘密不关任何人的事儿一样
I can keep a secret like nobody's business,
因为它本身就不关任何人的事儿
'cause it is nobody's business.
因为它是个秘密
'Cause it's a secret,
而且我没有把它说出来
and I'm keeping it!
马修刮后背吗
Does Marshall shave his back?
他才不刮呢 都是我替他刮 尼玛
No, I shave it for him. Damn it!
对了
Ooh!
我该给马修打个电话
I should call Marshall.
我敢肯定他也知道晚宴的事儿
I bet he's in on this.
如果他真的存在的话
If he really exists.
好吧
Okay.
我就不说我帮你隐瞒了
Setting aside the fact that I've kept your
搬去芝加哥的事这个事实
whole "Moving to Chicago" Thing a secret,
你现在不是应该穿成李伯拉斯的样子吗
aren't you supposed to be dressed like Liberace right now?
好吧 首先呢
Okay, first of all,
如果我现在就穿着服装出现
if I showed up in costume,
会破坏我之后华丽登场时的惊喜和壮观场面
it would steal from the surprise and spectacle of my grand entrance.
其次呢 我不打算这么玩了
And second of all, I'm not doing that.
为什么啊
Why not?
因为打扮成列勃拉斯很容易 但...
Because dressing like Liberace is easy, but...
啊 对 四四拍 E大调...
Uh, yes, 4/4, E-sharp...
大三度...
major...
好
Okay.
咱们来制造点美妙的音乐吧 如何
Let's make something beautiful, shall we?
我觉得今天练得差不多了
I think that's enough for today.
好了 我已经分析出事情会怎样进行了
Okay, I figured out how this is gonna go down.
我们会"急缺"冰块
We're gonna "Run out" Of ice,
然后罗宾会让我去买
and Robin's gonna ask me to go get some,
于是 你们瞧 整个小镇唯一一个
and lo and behold, the only place that sells ice
卖冰的地方就在一家真人激光枪游戏厅旁边
in this whole town is right next to the local laser taggery.
我走进去 然后...
I go inside and...
惊喜来啦
Surprise!
美好的晚宴 家人和朋友
Beautiful dinner, family and friends,
免费的游戏代币还有经典街机游戏
free game tokens and an off-road arcade game
已经装备了无限制涡轮驱动
that's rigged for unlimited turbos!
这是唯一蠢到家的...
That is the single stupidest...
同志们 真不敢相信
Guys, you aren't gonna believe this.
制冰机坏掉了
The ice machine is broken.
坏了是吧
Is it now?
真见鬼呢 这种事儿能有多大概率
Well, dog my cats, what are the chances?
好吧 现在怎么办呢
Huh? What do we do?
呃 我可以出去弄点冰回来
Well, I guess I could go get some ice.
哦 不用了 他们会派人去的
Uh, no, they'll send someone.
行 好吧 非让我去不可 我这就去
All right, fine. Twist my arm. I'll do it.
不过说真的 哈
But seriously, Hmm?
你们把那边都布置好了吗
did you get everything set up over there?
食物充足不 枪支齐备不
Do you have enough food, have enough guns?
有没有给斯丁森奶奶准备超大号背心 她可是...
Did you get a vest extender for Grandma Stinson? She's...
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
哦 宝贝 你好擅长掩饰哦 我好爱你哦
Oh, babe, you're so good at this. I love it.
好了 咱们在那边见吧
All right, I'll see you guys over there.
我是说 我马上回来
I mean, be right back.
巴尼 巴尼 这就是咱们的预演晚宴
Barney, Barney, this is our rehearsal dinner, okay?
不要离开这栋楼
Do not leave the premises.
跟我保证你哪儿也不去
Promise me you're not going anywhere.
好
Fine.
说出来
Say it.
说你保证你不会走
Say you promise you won't leave.
我保证我不会走
I promise I won't leave.
于是我走了 多么巧啊
So I left. And what do you know,
冰店的旁边就是一家真人激光枪游戏厅
the ice store is right next to a laser tag place!
根本不是 两家店相距六英里
No, it isn't! It's six miles away
而且在相反的方向
in the opposite direction.
而且我明明说了让你不要走
And I told you not to go!
是啊 不过你也说过
Yeah, well, you also told me
婚礼上不想要花熊
didn't want a ring bear at the wedding.
是花童
Ring bear-er!
我们都知道那会有多赞 重点是
We all know how great that's gonna be. The point is,
我顺着她的计划演
I played along with her plan,
还表现得很"自然" 这样就不会剧透惊喜
and I acted "Natural" So I wouldn't spoil the surprise.
我的七舅老爷啊
Oh, my goodness!
真人激光枪
Laser tag?!
或许我应该进去待一会儿呢
Maybe I should go in here for a minute,
只是去看看 没什么特别的理由
just check it out for no apparent reason.
哟 这是什么
And what's this?
我的免手提代币小腰包
My hands-free token satchel?
还有我的终身免费续杯根啤马克杯
And my free lifetime refill root beer mug?
那过去的两个月里
So for the past two months
我们借给你公寓用来
when we were letting you use our apartment
每周日晚上练习钢琴的时候
to practice the piano every Sunday night,
你都在干嘛
what were you doing?
哦 他是个MVP这就不算走步了吗
Oh, so that's not traveling 'cause he's the MVP?
MVP most valuable player 最有价值球员
搞什么
Come on!
巴尼去哪儿了 有人见到他了吗
Where's Barney? Has anyone seen him?
罗宾 泰德完全放弃了
Robin, Ted's totally bailing
为你和巴尼演奏钢琴的事
on playing the piano for you and Barney.
哦 真的吗 泰德 你并不需要这样做的呢
Oh, really? Ted, you didn't have to not do that.
不过真是谢谢啦
But thank you.
但他保证过的 承诺就是承诺
But he promised! A promise is a promise.
你不能明明说好要做一件事
You can't say you're gonna do something
却突然去做完全不同的另一件事
and then suddenly do something completely different!
你为什么对这事这么生气
Why are you getting so worked up about this?
因为 很显然 我是在为另外一件
Because, obviously, I'm worked up for a different
与之类似的事情生气
but somewhat similar reason.
该有人来问问我了吧
And someone should ask me about it!
不好意思 我现在没有时间陪你闹 莉莉
I'm sorry. I don't have time for your drama right now, Lily.
我的未婚夫失踪了
My fiance is missing.
马修被选中当法官了
Marshall got picked to be a judge.
他连问都没问我 就接受了这份工作
He took the job without even asking me.
意大利没戏了
Italy's off!
我的时间就是来陪你闹的
I have time for your drama.
-这么说 马修不能去意大利了吗  -如果他想当法官的话
-So, Marshall can't go to Italy? -Not if he wants to be a judge.
但我的意大利语现在说的可好了
And my Italian was getting so good.
特别的...
It was so...
\N我是一个工作到意大利的告别
\N好桑感
等等 你们俩已经把公寓转租了
But wait, you guys already sublet the apartment.
你的行李都收拾好了
I mean, you're already packed.
马修已经借走而且弄丢了我的罗塞达石碑
Marshall already borrowed and lost my Rosetta Stone.
刻有希腊文及埃及象形文字的石板 用于研究古埃及文字
这个自私的魂淡
That selfish bastard!
抱歉 莉儿 喂
Sorry, Lil. Hello.
好了 我也很愤怒
Okay, I'm mad, too.
你就该愤怒
I should hope so.
突然之间 他的梦想就比你的梦想更重要了吗
All of a sudden, his dream is more important than yours?
而且他还背着你做这事
And he did it behind your back.
魂淡
Bastardo!
他绝对不会故意伤害我的
He would never hurt me intentionally.
我会故意伤害他的
I'll hurt him intentionally.
极其魂淡
Molto bastardo!
你这样说真贴心
That's sweet of you to say.
你再过一百万年也打不过马修的
You could never take Marshall in a million years,
不过你这样说真贴心哈
but that's sweet of you to say.
好吧 很显然 巴尼去了真人激光枪游戏厅
Well, apparently, Barney went to the laser tag place
去找他那个惊喜预演晚宴
looking for a surprise rehearsal dinner.
结果他没找到 就威胁要
When he didn't find one, he threatened
把零食柜台售货员的脑袋
to dunk the snack bar guy's head
塞进装满滚烫玉米片的大桶里
into a vat of scalding nacho Whiz.
他现在被扣住了 等着警察过去呢
He's being held until the police arrive
我得来点苹果汁
I need your apple juice.
然后就变成这样了
And here we are.
现在 我觉得猜谜游戏已经进行得差不多了
Now, I believe this charade has gone on long enough.
咱们快去那个惊喜真人激光枪预演晚宴吧 好不好
Can we please get to the surprise laser tag rehearsal?
嘿 根本没有什么惊喜真人激光枪预演晚宴
Hey, there is no surprise laser tag rehearsal dinner!
好吧 但我能不能提一个相反的观点呢
Okay, but if I may offer an opposing view.
当然有啦
Of course there is!
这地方到处都是线索
This place is lousy with clues.
这个人真的是个保安吗
Is he even really a security guard?
他看起来无比像一个非巴基斯坦版的
Because he looks an awful lot like a non-Pakistani version
我办公室的三明治外卖送货员
of the guy who delivers sandwiches at my office.
而且...
Also...
"真人激光枪"和"预演晚宴"的字数一样多
"Laser tag" Has the same number of letters as "Rehearsal."
"真人激光枪"有8个字母 "预演晚宴"⑨个
Laser tag has eight, rehearsal has nine.
而且如果你重新排列一下这些字母 再加上一些字母
And if you rearrange the letters and add some other ones,
就会变成 "准备好 巴尼 为你最大的惊喜
it says, "Get ready, Barney, for the biggest surprise ever,
你个帅气的小..."
you handsome son of a..."
后面没有足够的字母来拼"王八蛋"了
and then not quite enough letters for "Bitch,"
不过你已经尽力了 罗宾
but good try, Robin.
这也太疯狂了 巴尼
This is crazy, Barney.
我们的婚姻不应该是这样的
We-We can't have a marriage like this.
婚姻必须建立在诚实以及信任
A marriage has to be built on honesty and trust
还有各种莉莉马修的那堆什么玩意儿上
and all of that Lily-and-Marshall crap.
我以为我们的婚姻是建立在诚实以及信任
I though our marriage was built on honesty and trust
还有各种莉莉马修的那堆什么玩意儿上
and all that Lily- and-Marshal crap.
我觉得真的好孤单
I just feel so alone right now.
但是 你并不孤单 有我在呢
Well, you're not. I'm here.
我知道你能守住秘密
And I know you can keep a secret.
是啊
Yeah, right.
要不这样
Tell you what.
要不我告诉你另外一个秘密吧
How about I let you in on another secret?
更大的秘密
Something bigger.
比芝加哥还大吗
Bigger than Chicago?
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
不 可否赏光
Nope. Want to do the honors?
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
计划有些小变动
there's been a slight change of plan.
好啦 好啦
Fine! Fine.
你说得对 罗宾
You're right, Robin.
婚姻不是整天恶作剧
Marriage isn't about playing crazy pranks.
不是处心积虑编一堆谎话
It isn't about telling long expertly crafted lies
去掩盖这些恶作剧...
to cover those pranks...
你是怎么解开手铐的
How'd you get out of those handcuffs?
...再请个演员扮演保安
...and hiring actors to play security guards
还斥巨资弄出来这些个大的要死的
and spending exorbitant amounts of money on things
假的真人激光枪牌子什么的
like giant, fake laser tag signs.
都不要 这关乎诚信
No, it's about honesty.
六码的冰鞋是吧
Size six skate, right?
是啊
Yeah.
正因如此 我要对你完全诚实
And in that spirit, I got to be honest.
从今往后
Every now and then,
我若对你撒谎 就是撒谎了
I am gonna lie to you. I just am.
是为了给你准备惊喜的
If it's in the interest of an amazing surprise, that is.
你会被忽悠 哄骗
You're gonna get bamboozled, hoodwinked.
算了 直接说出来吧
Heck, I'll just say it.
snow双关雪以及蒙混
你会被雪片般的谎言迷惑
You're gonna get snowed.
这里怎么下雪了
Why is it snowing in here?
穿好冰鞋
Put on the skates.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
去哪儿
Where?
我们是要去哪儿啊
Where are we going?
去预演晚宴啊 小傻瓜
To the rehearsal dinner, silly.
接下来就是见证奇迹的时刻
Let's get this party started.
什么
What?!
惊喜
Surprise!
这 这是怎么回事
What-What is going on?
我知道你非常想在加拿大度过这个周末
I know how much you wanted to be in Canada this weekend.
所以 我给你把加拿大搬过来了
So I brought Canada to you.
还有 这是韦恩•格雷斯基的签名照
Oh, and here's an autographed picture of Wayne Gretzky.
谢谢
Thanks.
还有这家伙也不是什么真的保安
And this guy's not really a security guard.
* 从前有一个男孩 *
Once there was this boy who
* 穿过无数西装 把传奇挂在嘴边 *
Wore a lot of suits and said that stuff was "Legendary"
* 他无数次击掌 *
He gave lots of high fives
* 无数次起誓 *
And swore...
* 婚姻与他无关 *
That he would never get married
* 他以为他非常坚决 *
He really thought he meant it
谢谢你让我参与其中
Thanks for letting me in on this.
就算到最后才有我的份
Even if it was at the very end.
不胜荣幸
My pleasure.
哦 顺便说一句
Oh, and by the way,
我还有一个秘密一直没说
there's one more secret I've been keeping.
那些个晚上我不是应该
All those nights I was supposed
在上钢琴课的吗
to be taking piano lessons?
我其实 是在上花样滑冰课
I was actually taking figure skating lessons!
* 从前有一个女孩 *
Once, there was this girl who...
孩子们 花样滑冰可不是只要两个月就能学会的
Kids, it takes more than two months to learn how to figure skate.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
-我会再回敬你一个的 知道不  -来呀
-I'm gonna get you back, you know? -Bring it.
* 无数次起誓 婚姻也与她无关 *
And swore she'd also never get married
* 她以为她非常坚决 *
She really thought she meant it.
万万没想到这都是你做的
I can't believe you did all of this.
你不是讨厌加拿大的吗
Hey, I thought you didn't like Canada.
开什么玩笑 我爱死加拿大了好吗
Are you kidding? I love Canada.
麝牛产于加拿大 多见于美洲原住民的图腾
麝了个牛的 这位是加拿大传奇医生 弗雷德里克•班廷吗
Holy musk ox, is that the legendary Canadian doctor Frederick Banting
哇哦
Whoa!
1924年 我发现了胰岛素
In 1924, I discovered insulin.
接招吧 糖尿病
Take that, diabetes.
看啊 曼尼托巴的子孙 诺曼•布雷基
Hey, look, it's Manitoba's native son, Norman Breakey.
不用客气 全世界人民
You're welcome, world.
好好享用我的发明 滚筒刷
Enjoy my invention, the paint roller.
艾伦•西克 加拿大演员 电台节目主持人
当然啦 大名鼎鼎的 艾伦•西克
And of course, you know Alan Thicke.
-嗨 你好啊  -你好
-Hey, hey, you... -Oh, hey.
这里就属你最美啦
...are the prettiest girl in the place.
噢 谢谢你 艾伦
Oh, thank you, Alan.
得了 得了 得了
All right, all right, all right.
见到你真高兴
Good to see you.
看啊 露易丝•普罗拉
Hey, look, it's Louise Poirier,
好像是在发明了神奇内衣的公司上班
who I think worked for the company that probably created Wonderbra.
滚蛋吧 老掉牙的拖带
au revoir vieille gaine façonné
行了 行了
Okay, okay.
加拿大助攻赢了两次世界大战
Canadians also helped win two world wars...
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
分别为加拿大歌手 演员 作家 花花公子封面女郎
并且赐予了这个世界 尼尔•扬 威廉•夏纳
...and gave the world Neil Young, William Shatner,
莱昂纳德•科恩 帕米拉•安德森
Leonard Cohen, Pamela Anderson,
四分之一个巴尼•斯丁森
one quarter of Barney Stinson,
方便土豆泥 以及最最重要的 你
instant mashed potatoes, and best of all, you.
谢谢
Thank you.
HIMYM字幕组 谢谢观看
欢迎关注字幕组新浪微博及人人网公共主页@HIMYM字幕组
郑重么么哒所有的么么哒
下周好像要停播么么哒 年终一定要快乐么么哒